Collins mss., 1926-2001 LMC 2411
Lilly Library
- VIII. Clippings (Box 11)
  - Chess Life, June 20, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Chess Strategies and Analyses (Box 11)
  - Clippings and Folios, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Clippings and Notes from Books (Box 11)
  - Collins Kids (Box 11)
  - Duchamp, Marcel and Alexina (Box 11)
  - Ethel Collins' Memorial (Box 11)
  - Game Clippings (Box 11)
  - Games by USCF Members, 1960; 1968 (Box 11)
  - John Cage (Box 11)
  - JWC Clippings, 1959 (Box 11)
  - JWC, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Literary Market (Box 11)
  - Marcus and Bryan Brown (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Chess (Box 11)
  - New York Chess Clubs (Box 11)
  - NT, June 27, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Other (Box 11)
  - Petrosian Crushed in 26 Moves by Lloyd S. Smith, undated (Box 11)
  - Photocopies of Chess Book Title Pages (Box 11)
  - Related Game Clippings (Box 11)
  - Russian News, October, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Sicilian Defense (Box 11)
  - Ventnor City Invitation Chess Tournament, 1939 (Box 11)
  - What I Discovered about Poop Glover The Saturday Evening Post, 1976 (Box 11)
  - WWII News, 1939-1945 (Box 11)
- IX. Memorabilia (Box 11)
  Organized into the following subseries: Tournament Programs and Bulletins; and Other.
  - Tournament Programs and Bulletins (Box 11)
    - 16eme Olympiade D'Echecs, Israel, 1964 (Box 11)
    - Tallinn, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Mexico, 1978; 1980 (Box 11)
    - 1945-1975 (Box 11)
    - 1981-1996 (Box 11)
  - Other (Box 11)
    - Armed Forces Chess Tournament Dinner, 1967; 1969 (Box 11)
    - Blank Cards (Box 11)
    - International Chess Calendars, 1990-1998 (Box 12)
    - Israel Brochures and Pamphlets, 1970s-1980s (Box 12)
    - Ordination of Reverend Lombardy, May 27, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Rolywholover: A Circus, John Cage Exhibition, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Township of Dover Proclamation, Jan. 8, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
- X. Photographs (Box 12)
  Organized into the following subseries: General; and Framed.
  - General (Box 12)
    - Chess Players and Enclosed Notes (Box 12)
    - Christmas Photos from Siggn and Silja, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Collins, 1987; undated (Box 12)
    - Collins' Apartment, undated (Box 12)
    - Collins and Friends, undated (Box 12)
    - Collins and Others (Box 12)
    - Collins and Others, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Collins and Others, Negatives, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Collins and Others Eating in Reykjavik (From Fischer/Spassky Album #4), 1972 (Box 12)
    - Collins, Ethel and Jack, Miscellaneous Negatives (Box 12)
    - Collins Kids (Box 12)
    - Collins Kids' Rolywholover Circus, April 25, 1994 (Box 12)
    - CK to Israel, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - Concord, Collins Kids vs. Iceland, 1988-1989 (Box 12)
    - Dale, Arthur, August 3, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Enlarged Photos from Parsippany, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Enlarged Photos of John and Ethel, August, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Family Portraits (Box 12)
    - Fischer and Weinstein, October 1956; October 1957 (Box 12)
    - Fischer as a young boy playing chess with Collins, undated (Box 12)
    - Fischer playing Collins with Weinstein in background, undated (Box 12)
    - Goldmanski and Others, undated (Box 12)
    - Helms, Hermann, 1955 (Box 12)
    - Iceland, 1995-1996 (Box 12)
    - Jack and Ethel Christmas Card Prints, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Jack on Tricycle, February, 1993 (Box 12)
    - John T. Collins' Band, undated (Box 12)
    - JWC Photos by Wolff Weber (Box 12)
    - JWC Picture Gallery, Hall of Fame (Box 12)
    - John Cage Photos, 1971 (Box 12)
    - Karpov, Anatoly (Box 12)
    - Lasker, Edward and Wolff, Louis, June 1978; undated (Box 12)
    - Lasker, Emanuel (Box 12)
    - Olafsson, Fridrik, undated (Box 12)
    - Lyman, Shelby, January, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Personal Framed Photos, undated (Box 12)
    - Photos from Jack's Apartment (Box 12)
    - Stanley B. Winters, 1991; 1993; undated (Box 12)
    - Tennessee, Lilla, and Friend (Box 12)
    - Vermont, Summer 1990 (Box 12)
    - X-Ray of Collins' Pelvis at Age 2 (Box 12)
    - August, 1958 (Box 12)
    - September, 1967 (Box 12)
    - April, 1989 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Framed (Box 12)
    - Ethel Collins with Two Children (Box 13)
    - Framed Photos of Jack (Box 13)
    - Jack and man holding a cup (Box 13)
    - Jack playing chess with Clara Collins (Box 13)
    - Jack posed with a child at Awards Banquet (Box 13)
    - Jack's Godchild in Reykjavik, Iceland (Box 13)
    - John Philip Sousa and Band, (John T. Collins, far left) (Box 13)
    - John T. Collins and others in military attire (Box 13)
    - John W. Collins and Hermann Helms (Box 13)
    - JWC playing chess (Box 13)
    - Louis Wolff as WWI Soldier (Box 13)
    - Photos of Apartment Buildings, (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - Photos of Houses (Box 13)
    - Portrait of Baby (Box 13)
    - Unn the Deep Minded (Box 29)
    - Portrait of Soldiers (Box 29)
    - Portrait of John T. Collins (Box 29)
    - Jack playing chess with children (Box 29)
    - Portrait of Unidentified Couple (Box 29)
    - Portrait of Wilhelm Steinitz (Box 29)
    - Portraits of Children (Box 29)
    - Portraits of Jack and Ethel (Box 29)
    - Woman in Fur Coat, 1955 (Box 29)
    - Unidentified, July, 1985 (Box 29)
    - Unidentified Framed Photos (Box 29)
- XI. Albums and Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook in Ethel Collins' Memory, (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - John T. Collins Photos and Clippings (Box 12)
  - JWC Clippings #1 (Box 12)
  - JWC Clippings #2 (Box 12)
  - JWC Clippings #4 (Box 12)
  - Chess Clippings, Scrapbook #1 (Box 12)
  - Chess Scrapbook #2 (Box 12)
  - Early Scores, Clippings and Letters of Jack (Box 12)
  - Jack's Very First Album of Chess Clippings, etc. (Box 12)
  - U.S. Open, Lincoln, 1975 (Box 15)
  - NYS Tournament, Corning, 1969 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Open, Rochester and NYS Tournament, Buffalo, 1958; 1956 (Box 15)
  - Bobby Karpov, Korschnoi at JWC Home, Kasparov, 1958; Apr. 1979; Aug. 1983; 1988 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Open, Atlanta, 1967 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Open, Cleveland, 1958 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Amateur Team Tournament, Somerset, 1992 (Box 15)
  - U.S. Chess Festival, Concord, U.S., Iceland, Israel #1, 1984 (Box 15)
  - JWC #1 (Box 15)
  - JWC #2 (Box 15)
  - JWC #3 (Box 15)
  - JWC #5 (Box 15)
  - Iceland #1-A, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Iceland #8, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Fischer-Spassky #1, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Fischer-Spassky #2, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Fischer-Spassky #4, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Fischer-Spassky #5, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Fischer-Spassky #6, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Fischer-Spassky #7, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Collins Kids #1 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #2 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #3 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #4 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #5 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #6 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #7 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #8 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #9 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #10 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids #11 (Box 17)
  - Collins Kids Party at Nils Kessler's, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids Amateur Tournament, Atlantic City, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids Match, Parties at Jack's House, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids West Point&, 1977; 1978 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids City Hall, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids U.S. Amateur Team Tournament, Somerset, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids, West Point, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids U.S. Amateur Team, 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - Collins Kids West Point, 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - [Multiple events; Primarily Collins Kids], 1980-1984 (Box 18)
  - Iceland Safari #1, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Iceland Safari #2, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Icelandic Saga #1, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Iceland Saga #2, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Iceland Saga #3, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Iceland Saga #4, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Part of Iceland Saga, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Iceland Saga, Gift from Iceland, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Iceland, CK Safari #4, June 1985 (Box 20)
  - CK, Israel Scenes, 1983-1984 (Box 20)
  - Iceland Safari #1, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Iceland Safari #2, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Iceland Safari #3, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Iceland Saga, Concord #1, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Iceland Safari #1, 1982-1983 (Box 20)
  - Iceland Safari #2, 1982-1983 (Box 20)
  - Iceland Safari #3, 1982-1983 (Box 20)
  - Icelandic Safari #1, June 1985 (Box 21)
  - Icelandic Safari #2, June 1985 (Box 21)
  - Icelandic Safari #3, June 1985 (Box 21)
  - Iceland Safari #5, June 1985 (Box 21)
  - CK vs. Israeli Kids, Israel, 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - CK vs. Israeli Kids, Israel, 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - U.S. Chess Festival, U.S., Iceland, Israel, 1984 (Box 21)
  - Collins Kids Portfolio, 1977 (Box 21)
  - CK, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Saga, CK Kids vs. Iceland, 1990 (Box 22)
  - CK vs. Harvard, Chang-Aspis Award, 1986 (Box 22)
  - CK Teams, U.S. Amateur Team Tournament, 1988 (Box 22)
  - Collins Kids, USAT, Somerset, 1990 (Box 22)
  - CK Icelandic Saga Thanksgiving, Zamora, 1990 (Box 22)
  - CK Matches at JWC Home, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Nawrose Nur, 1990 (Box 22)
  - Jack's Russian Kids (Box 22)
  - Untitled To Jack and Ethel from Robert (Box 22)
  - Jack's Kids vs. Iselananders Concord, 1990 (Box 22)
  - Jack, Simol at Dalton, March 1988 (Box 23)
  - U.S. Amateur Team Tournaments, 1986-1987 (Box 23)
  - Iceland Saga #1, 1988 (Box 23)
  - CK Iceland Saga #2, 1988 (Box 23)
  - CK Iceland Saga #3, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Gurevich-Adams CK Match #1, 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Gurevich-Adams CK Match, 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Florida Nicky and Jack, 1988 (Box 23)
  - CK Icelandic Saga #1, July 1986 (Box 23)
  - CK Icelandic Saga #2, July 1896 (Box 23)
  - U.S. Amateur Team Tournament, Somerset, 1985 (Box 23)
  - U.S. Amateur Team Tournament, Somerset, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Jack Alone #1 (Box 24)
  - Jack and Chess Friends #1 (Box 24)
  - Jack and Chess Friends #2 (Box 24)
  - Jack's Chess Friends #3 (Box 24)
  - JWC Chess Friends #4 (Box 24)
  - Jack's Friends #5 (Box 24)
  - JWC Chess Friends #6 (Box 24)
  - JWC Chess Events and People (Box 24)
  - Chess Cards, etc., Special Keepsakes (Box 25)
  - Letters to Jack #1 (Box 25)
  - Letters to Jack #2 (Box 25)
  - Lombardy Cards and Letters (Box 25)
  - Letters and Clippings to Jack #3 (Box 25)
  - Letters To Jack #4 (Box 26)
  - Happy Birthday! (Box 26)
  - Clippings Regarding Jack Clara had kept over many years (Box 26)
  - JWC Clippings #3 (Box 26)
  - Letters to John #5 Hall of Fame (Box 26)
  - JWC U.S. Chess Hall of Fame and Our Trip, 1991 (Box 26)
  - [Jack's Handmade Toy Soldiers] (Box 26)
  - Silyja 1 (Box 27)
  - Silyja 2 (Box 27)
  - Untitled, [black album with floral accent], undated (Box 27)
  - Gift from Bennie, Ethel's Favorite Father, March 1991 (Box 27)
  - Untitled; date unclear... or (covers multiple events: Danny's Birthday Party Pearl and Allen Kaufman Wedding Sig-Waters- and Collins, 1955-1986; 1979-1983; May 1983; 1980; 1979) (Box 27)
  - CK Sal Matera: Wedding Ann and Sal, undated (Box 27)
  - Untitled; multiple events: Alan and Sara Wedding Chess Friends (no particular time or place); Trip with Al and Sara - St. Louis, Canada, Vermont, 1958; 1956- (Box 27)
  - Collins' House (Box 27)
  - Collins' New Year's Parties, 1971 (Box 27)
  - Jack, Ethel/ New Year's Day at Home 1988, New Year's 1988 (Box 27)
  - Louis J. Wolff #1 (Box 28)
  - Louis J. Wolff #2 (Box 28)
- XII. Audio-Visual (Box 28)
  - Videocassettes (Box 28)
    - World Chess Championship, Show #103 "Bobby Fischer's Chess", 1987; (4 copies) (Box 28)
    - The Works - Duchamp (Box 28)
    - Ethel's Birthday (Box 28)
    - The Cross-Country Adventure, July 25-August 13, 1991 (Box 28)
    - Iceland Chess, PBS Chess Tournament, 9/23/84; (3 copies) (Box 28)
  - Audiocassettes (Box 28)
    - Accompanying Note (Box 28)
    - Andreas Vollenweider, William Ackerman, Kripalu Instrumentalists (Box 28)
    - Collins Service, 5/25/93 (Box 28)
    - Ethel B Collins Memorial, 5/25/93 (Box 28)
    - John and Ethel Collins: Start of a bio & people they knew (by John) (Box 28)
    - Unidentified, Black Scotch C-90 (Box 28)
    - Kor Langholtskirkju Land Mins Fodur [Icelandic songs?] (Box 28)
    - Joseph Matera (Box 28)
    - Vivaldi Concertos (Box 28)
    - Discussions, Interviews of Chess People/Jack's Dictations, (16 tapes in black case) (Box 28)
    - John W. Collins' Stories (Box 28)
    - Jack's [ones?] (Box 28)
- XIII. Realia (Box 30)
  - Autograph Book, Late, 1980s-1990s (Box 30)
  - Wooden Box (once contained Jack's Bios of Chess Players) (Box 32)
  - Tin containing Jack's Paper Soldiers (Box 33)
  - Butterfly box (once contained Jack's early manuscripts) (Box 34)
  - Autograph Book, 1927 (Box 35)
  - Blue Purse (Box 35)
  - Chess Coaster (Box 35)
  - Flag Chess Olympiad in Manila, 1992 (Box 35)
  - Pin I Love the U.S. Team, (2) (Box 35)
  - Pin New York Salutes 1st American World Chess Champion (Box 35)
  - Pin Scholastic Team Chess Championship, March 20, 1994 (Box 35)
  - Set of Chess Player pins (in Russian), [To Mr. Collins from Michael Perelshteyn] (Box 35)
  - Sterling Silver Chess Piece, [Gift to Jack from Louis J. Wolff, ca. 1975] (Box 35)